Guide to the Robert E. Simon, Jr. papers, 1960-2006
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Robert E. Simon, Jr. papers
1960-2006
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
Robert E. (Robert Edward) Simon, 1914-
C0162
7.5 linear feet (15 boxes)
The collection consists of newsclippings, promotional material and booklets relating to Reston. Also included are printed material, publications, scrapbooks, and his speeches and paperwork from various conferences he attended at different universities around the country.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Robert E. Simon Jr. in three section first on May 7, 1992, second on August 9, 1993 and the final donation was made on September 15, 2008.
Biographical Information
Robert E. Simon, Jr., was born in New York City in 1914. After graduating from Harvard, Simon took over the family real estate management and development business. In 1961, with the proceeds from the sale of a family property, Carnegie Hall, Simon purchased 6,750 acres of land in Fairfax County, Virginia, which would become Reston, Virginia. Reston is now recognized as the foremost Planned Community in the United States. Simon's Planned Community, or new town, emphasized the quality of life for the individual and provided a community where people could live, work, and play.
Scope and Content
The Robert E. Simon Jr. Papers are comprised of newsclippings, promotional material and booklets relating to Reston. Also included are printed material, publications and scrapbooks. Robert E. Simon Jr. included in his donation his speeches and paperwork from various conferences he attended at different universities around the country.
Series one is titled correspondence and is dated from 1975 to 2001. The series is small and is only in box 1. Some of the correspondence is between Robert E. Simon Jr. and Martha Pennino. Also included in the series are invitations for various speaking engagements.
Series two is titled Reston General Information and is dated from 1960 to 1990. The series is contained within boxes 1 through 4. In this series there are various documents from Reston, including promotional material, newsclippings and zoning information.
Series three is titled Reston Community Centers and is dated from 1963 to 1991. The series is contained in box 4. The series is information from different organizations in Reston such as North Golf Course and Reston Day Care.
Series four is titled Reston Finance and is dated from 1963 to 1976. The series is contained in boxes 4 and 5. The series is general information on the finances of Reston. Included in the series are documents on taxes, consulting firms and various other sources.
Series five is titled Building Projects and is dated from 1961 to 1975. The series is contained in boxes 5 and 6. The series has information dealing with different projects in Reston from various architectural firms and other corporations involved in the projects.
Series six is titled National File and is dated from 1964 to 1987. The series is contained in boxes 6 and 7. The series includes information from national organizations such as the League of Women Voters and Housing and Urban Development (HUD).
Series seven is titled Conferences and is dated from 1964 to 1987. The series is contained in boxes 7 through 10. The information in this series is from various conferences that Robert E. Simon Jr. attended during these years. Included are Harvard University, Columbia University and other universities in the United States that had conferences relating to Planned Communities.
Series eight is titled Planned Communities and is dated from 1962 to 1975. The series contained in boxes 10 and 11. The documents in this series is information from different planned communities. There are international communities in Great Britain and communities within the United States, such as Columbia, Maryland.
Series nine is titled Media and is dated from 1960 to 2003. The series is contained in boxes 11 and 12. The series is comprised of negatives, slides, photographs, videotapes and a single reel. The videotapes are mostly interviews with Robert E. Simon Jr. about Reston.
Series ten is titled Oversize and is dated from 1960 to 2006. The series is contained in boxes 13 through 15. The series is mostly newsclippings from the 1960s and more recent magazine publications from the twenty-first century. The articles all relate to Reston and the developments there.
Arrangement
Organized into 10 series.
Series 1: Correspondence, 1975-2001 (Box 1)
Series 2: Reston General Information, 1960-1990 (Boxes 1-4)
Series 3: Reston Community Centers, 1963-1991 (Box 4)
Series 4: Reston Finance, 1963-1976 (Boxes 4-5)
Series 5: Building Projects, 1961-1975 (Boxes 5-6)
Series 6: National File, 1964-1987 (Boxes 6-7)
Series 7: Conferences, 1964-1987 (Boxes 7-10)
Series 8: Planned Communities, 1962-1975 (Boxes 10-11)
Series 9: Media, 1960-2003 (Boxes 11-12)
Series 10: Oversize, 1960-2006 (Boxes 13-15)
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives also holds many other collections on the history of Reston and Northern Virginia.
Index Terms
Persons:
Simon, Robert E. (Robert Edward), 1914-
Geographical Names:
Reston (Va.)
Subjects:
Housing--Virginia--Reston.; Planned communities--Virginia--Reston.
Document Types:
Photographic negatives.; Photographic prints.; Slides.; Video recordings.
Contents List
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1975-2001; (0.5 boxes)
  Series one is titled correspondence. The series has some correspondence between Robert E. Simon Jr. and Martha Pennino and invitations for various speaking engagements. The series is dated from 1975 to 2001.
  - Correspondence with Martha Pennino, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    266.6
  - Invitations, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    267.2
  - Invitation to Speak (Lectures), 1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    267.4
  - Memberships, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    267.5
  - Invitations, 1979-1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    267.3
  - Correspondence with Stockholders, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    274.5
  - Reston Correspondence, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    274.14
  - Memorabilia Letters, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    266.2
  - Reston Correspondence, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    274.15
  - Correspondence with Fritz Gutheim, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    267.6
  - Robert E. Simon Resume, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    266.1a
- Series 2: Reston General Information 1960-1990, (3 boxes)
  Series two is titled Reston General Information. In this series there are various documents from Reston, including promotional material and zoning information. The series is dated from 1960 to 1990.
  - Homeowners Association Declaration of Protective Covenants, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 12)
    267.11
  - Maps, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 13)
    275.11
  - Zoning Amendment, 1961 and 1962 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    275.7
  - Personnel Organization Chart, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    275.9
    - Gulf Reston, Inc. (Organizational Chart), October 4, 1967; 1.
    - Reston Employees As At November 30, 1963, 3.
    - Reston Va., Inc. (Organizational Chart), 1966; 6.
  - Closing Statement Palindrome, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    274.3
  - Press and Magazine Coverage, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    270.15
  - Gulf-Reston Fact Sheet, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    275.5
  - Ownership Guaranteers for Morgan Loan, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    274.2
  - Reston Stockholder Report, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    274.4
  - Promotional Ceremonies, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    275.1
  - International Press Coverage of Reston, Virginia, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    395.2
  - Fairfax County Historical Highlights From 1607, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    395.4
  - Press Reports on Reston, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    395.3
  - First Homeowners Association (Corporate Data), 1967 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    267.10
  - Reston Foundation, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    266.3
  - Gulf-Reston, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    273.1
  - Forest's Edge, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 12)
    395.7
  - Press and Magazine Coverage, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    270.14
  - Reston Speeches, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    268.14
  - Hercer Corporation Regarding Gulf Reston Stock, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    274.1
  - Land Appraisal Felt and Company, 1980s (Box 3, Folder 3)
    275.12
  - Washington Post Clippings, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    275.3
  - Planning Summary: A.D. Little Incorporated, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    275.8
  - Land Development in Reston, Virginia, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    268.15
  - News Clippings, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    395.9
  - Reston, Virginia: Map and Newsclipping, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    267.8
    - Reston, Virginia (Promotional Booklet), ca. 1963; 1.
  - Promotional Materials, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    395.8
  - Reston Handbook, Reston Founder's Day Program, 1986 and April 5, 2014 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    395.5
  - Notes, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Reston Information, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    276.13
  - Reston Town Center, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    395.6
- Series 3: Reston Community Centers 1963-1991 (0.5 boxes), (9 folders)
  Series three is titled Reston Community Centers. The series is information from different organizations in Reston such as the Reston Day Care. The series is dated from 1963 to 1991.
  - Reston on North Golf Course, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    266.1
  - Press Review: Lake Anne Village Center, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    395.1
  - Reston: Child Care, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    267.12
    - Day Care for Children and Training for Women, 1964 or 1967; 1.
    - Proposed Children's Center, ca. 1967; 6.
  - Lake Anne Center, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    266.4
  - Conference on Community Child Care, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    267.13
  - Industrial Center Reston, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    267.14
  - Loeb Center, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    271.8
  - Reston Day Care Center, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    267.9
  - Reston Child Care Center, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    270.12
- Series 4: Reston Finance 1963-1976, (1 box)
  Series four is titled Reston Finance. Included in the series are documents on taxes, consulting firms and various other sources. The series is dated from 1963 to 1976.
  - Financing Company's Oil Companies, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    274.10
  - Financing Gulf Oil, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    273.3
  - General Financing, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    274.9
  - Atlantic Refinancing, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    274.11
  - Tax Exemption Bond Issue, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    274.8
  - Financing, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    274.7
  - Mortgage Application, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    275.2
  - General Electric Financing, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    274.12
  - Robert Gladstone and Association (Economic Consultants), 1965 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    270.1
  - Kaplan Gans Associates (Marshall Kaplan) Consulting Firm, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    270.2
  - Staten Island Chamber of Commerce, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    268.11
  - Loan Information, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    266.5
  - Facts, Statistics (General), 1967 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    269.4
  - John Hancock Mutual Life Insurance Company, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    274.6
  - Long Range Forecast Through 1982, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    274.13
  - Thompson and Benjamin (Consultants), 1971 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    270.3
  - Financial History, Cost, Report on Overall Maintenance, Cluster Association, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    267.15
  - Southern Duchess Chamber of Commerce, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    272.2
- Series 5: Building Projects 1961-1975 (1 box), (1 box)
  Series five is titled Building Projects. The series has information dealing with different projects in Reston from various architectural firms. The series is dated from 1961 to 1975.
  - Architectural Firms: Harland and Bartholomew, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    270.9
  - Real Estate Research Corporation, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    266.17
  - Acoustics Kadaras, Michael Jr.: Engineers, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    270.10
  - General Architecture, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    275.4
  - Larry Smith and Company (Consultants), 1963 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    266.16
  - Architectural Firms Perkins and Willis, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    266.12
  - Architectural Firms: Edward H. Noakes Associates, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    266.11
  - Architectural Firms Chas M. Goodman Associates, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    266.8
  - Architectural Firms: Caudill, Rowlett, Scott, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    270.7
  - Architectural Firms: James Fanning, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    270.6
  - Architectural Firms: Dan Kiley, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    270.5
  - Architectural Firms: Keyes, Lehbridge and Condon, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    266.7
  - Architectural Firms: W.B. Ford Design, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    266.10
  - Architectural Firms: Herman Blum, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    270.8
  - Architectural Firm: Rouse, Duben, Duben and Venture, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    266.13
  - Architectural Firms: Geddes, Brecher and Qualls, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    266.9
  - Architectural Firms: Cloethiel Smith and Associates, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    266.15
  - Doxiadis Associates, Incorporated (Consulting Firm), 1968 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    270.11
  - Consultants and Contractors: Eustance and Horwitz, 1970s (Box 6, Folder 16)
    275.6
  - Pratt Institute School of Architecture, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    276.6
  - Whittlesey and Conklin (Architects), 1975 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    270.4
  - American Institute of Architects, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    271.27
- Series 6: National File 1964-1987, (1 box)
  Series six is titled National File. The series includes information from national organizations such Housing and Urban Development (HUD). The series is dated from 1964 to 1987.
  - Washington Real Estate Board, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    269.9
  - American Institute of Real Estate: Appraisers Speech Washington D.C., 1964 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    267.1
  - Robert C. Weaver Speech, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    269.10
  - New Towns/ New Towns vs. Rehabilitation, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    269.8
  - League of Women Voters, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    271.14
  - Chamber of Commerce, U.S., 1965 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    272.1
  - National Retail Merchants Association, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    271.3
  - National Advisory Commission on Rural Poverty-Smithsonian Institution, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    271.5
  - National Commission on Urban Problems (Senator Douglas), 1967 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    271.4
  - Urban Development Proposals, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    269.7
  - Library of Presidential Papers, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    271.18
  - Housing and Urban Development (HUD) New Communities Speech, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    271.2
  - Housing and Urban Development (HUD) Denver, Colorado Speech, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    271.20
  - Federal Housing, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    269.6
  - Housing and Urban Development (HUD)- Workshop on New Communities, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    271.1
  - Institute of Human Relations, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    271.11
  - American Society of Planning Officials, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    271.25
  - Housing and Urban Development (HUD) Grant Documents, 1976 and 1986 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    273.2
  - Crime Institute, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    272.3
- Series 7: Conferences 1965-1987, (3 boxes)
  Series seven is titled Conferences. The information in this series is from various conferences that Robert E. Simon Jr. attended during these years. The series is dated from 1964 to 1987.
  - Howard University-Real Estate Club For Land, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    271.24
  - Yale University, New Haven, Connecticut, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    268.8
  - Building Research Institute Conference, Washington D.C., 1965 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    272.14
  - American Institute of Real Estate Appraisers: Chicago, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    271.26
  - Society of Real Estate Appraisers Washington D.C. (Speeches), 1965 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    268.7
  - Regional Planning Association Columbia University, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    268.13
  - Brander's University Speech, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    272.9
  - Joint Center for Urban Studies (M.I.T. and Harvard), 1966 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    271.13
  - Bennington Speech: Vermont, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    272.10
  - Cornell University, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    272.6
  - Real Estate Board, New York: Shopping Center Committee, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    276.10
  - Society for Advancement of Management War Chester, Massachusetts, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    268.6
  - Virginia Cultural Development Study Commission, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    268.12
  - West Virginia Center for Appalachian Studies and Development (Speech), 1967 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    269.11
  - Metropolitan Housing and Planning Council of Chicago, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    271.7
  - New Jersey Federation of Planning Officials, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    271.10
  - Columbia University, School of Architecture, 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    272.7
  - Syracuse University, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    268.9
  - Bard Awards Speech, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    272.12
  - New School: New York City-New York Land Use (Senator Douglas), 1968 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    271.9
  - University of North Carolina Seminar, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    276.11
  - Statement by Robert E. Simon, Jr. Before National Advisory Commission on Rural Poverty, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    1.4
    - Statement by Robert E. Simon, Jr. Before the National Advisory Commission, ca. 1967; 1.
  - Harbor Islands Commission-Boston, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    271.15
  - Quebec-Association of Industrial Designers, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    276.5
  - Place To LIve, A Exhibit: Madison, Wisconsin, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    276.7
  - Rochester Lincoln Bank Speech, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    268.2
  - Building Research Institute Conference Chicago, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    267.7
  - Lion's Club Speech, Rochester, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    268.3
  - University of North Carolina New Towns Research Seminar, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    276.12
  - Cornell University Speech: "The University of Community Builder", 1970 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    272.5
  - John Jay College (New York University) Seminar, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    271.12
  - Peacock Hill Seminar-Williamsburg, Virginia, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    276.3
  - Rochester Chamber of Commerce, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    268.17
  - Rochester Builders Association, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    268.16
  - Northern Colorado Foundation; University of Washington D.C., 1971 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    276.14
  - Cornell Conference, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    272.4
  - Cornell Speech, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    271.19
  - University of Rochester Speech, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    268.4
  - New School: New York City "Managing New Towns", 1971 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    276.8
  - Yale-Department of Agriculture, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    268.1
  - Governor's Conference-Hawaii, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    271.16
  - Bedford Village Speech, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    272.11
  - Real Estate Shopping Center Symposium, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    276.9
  - Urban Life Center: Columbia, Maryland, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    268.10
  - Speeches-General (Index Cards), 1972 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    269.2
  - Summary Sheets-Speeches, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    269.3
  - Rutgers University-Planned Unit Development (PUD) Conference, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    268.5
  - Speech Material and Quotes, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    269.5
  - Pennsylvania State University-National Urban Growth Seminar, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    276.2
  - Rochester, Harvard Business School, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    276.4
  - Pennsylvania State University, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Aspen-International Design Conference, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    272.13
  - Peter Minuet Speech, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    276.1
  - Fordham University Speech, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    271.23
  - Cornell School of Design, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    272.8
  - Harvard University, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    271.22
  - Wharton Graduate Real Estate Association, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    269.12
  - Montclair, New Jersey-Adult Urban Studies, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    271.6
  - Dutchess County Planners, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Speech File-Miscellaneous, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    269.1
  - George Mason-Bill Nicosin, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    271.17
- Series 8: Planned Communities 1962-1975 (1 boxes), (1 boxes)
  The documents in this series is information from different planned communities. There are international communities in Great Britain and communities within the United States, such as Columbia, Maryland.
  - Tapiola, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    504.2
  - Tantalon, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    504.6
  - Stevenage, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    504.7
  - English New Towns (Satellite Cities), 1962 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    504.1
  - English New Towns (Satellite Cities), 1962 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Satellite Cities, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    504.8
  - Irvine Ranch, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    504.3
  - Columbia-James Rouse, 1973-1975 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    504.5
- Series 9: Media 1960-2003, (1.5 boxes)
  Series eight is titled Media. The series is comprised of negatives, slides, photographs, videotapes and a reel. The series is dated from 1960 to 2003.
  - Reston Slides, 1960s (Box 11, Folder 5)
    394.4
  - Reston Negatives, 1960s (Box 11, Folder 6)
    394.11
  - Photos: Sunset Hills Farm, Fairfax County, Virginia: Gift of Robert Simon, 1960s (Box 11, Folder 7)
    395.10
  - Reston Photos, 1960s (Box 11, Folder 8)
    394.6
  - Reston Photos, 1960s (Box 11, Folder 9)
    394.7
  - Reston Photos, 1960s (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Reston Photos, 1960s (Box 12, Folder 1)
    394.9
  - Reston Photos, 1960s (Box 12, Folder 2)
    394.10
  - Reston Photos, 1960s (Box 12, Folder 3)
    394.5
  - Reflections Lake Anne School, 1982-1983 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    14.1
  - Lake Anne School-Interview of Robert Simon (VHS), 1983 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    14.1; Access copy available on DVD. 39 minutes, 58 seconds.
  - Conversation with Robert E. Simon (VHS), May 20,1979 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    154.2; Access copy available on DVD. 29 minutes.
  - Conversation with Robert E. Simon (VHS), May 20, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    154.2
  - Unedited Copy of Robert E. Simon: Interviewer Bob Dix (VHS), 1993 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    485.2
  - Interview with Robert E. Simon and Jane Wilhelm (VHS) (Box 12, Folder 9)
    394; Access copy available on DVD. 18 minutes, 48 seconds.
  - Robert E. Simon (VHS), July 1, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    394; Access copy available on DVD. 30 minutes, 01 seconds.
  - Robert E. Simon Tribute(VHS) (Box 12, Folder 11)
    394; Access copy available on DVD. 12 minutes, 15 seconds.
  - "Reston" Final Print from Internet (Box 12, Folder 12)
    394.3
- Series 10: Oversize 1960-2006, (3 boxes)
  Series nine is titled Oversize. The series is mostly newsclippings and articles that relate to Reston and the developments there. The series is dated from 1960 to 2006.
  - Planning Magazine, 2006 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    1.1
  - Northern Virginia Magazine, 2006 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    1.2
  - Grapevine Home and Travel, 2006 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    1.3
  - Linden Springs at Wiehle Virginia, 2000s (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Virginia Living Magazine, 2005 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    1.5
  - Newsclipping: The Evening Star, Suburban Town Houses "A Popular Trend", 1964 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    396.1
  - Newsclipping: The Evening Star, "Fairfax Voters OK School Bonds, 5-1", The Washington Post, "Grant to Help Fairfax Plan Reston Schools" and Falls Church Sun Echo, "Design Research For Reston's Schools Started", 1963 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    396.2
  - Newsclipping: The Evening Star, Suburban Town Houses "A Popular Trend", 1964 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    396.3
  - Newsclipping: American Engineer, "Glenn Saunders, Jr., P.E. The Challenge To Create", 1960s (Box 14, Folder 4)
    396.4